{
    "questions":[
        {
            "question":"What Resource Group primarily does ? ",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Physical grouping of resources"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Logical grouping of resources"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Avoids the clutter in azure portal"
                },
                {
                    "D":"All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"B",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following statements are true for Azure cloud ? ",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"It is a Microsoft cloud platform "
                },
                {
                    "B":"It provides SAAS , IAAS and PAAS "
                },
                {
                    "C":"It is a public cloud"
                },
                {
                    "D":"All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which is not a region available as a Azure region ? ",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Central India"
                },
                {
                    "B":"South Africa North"
                },
                {
                    "C":"West India"
                },
                {
                    "D":"North India"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the primary purpose of Azure Functions ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Data warehousing"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Automated resource management"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Serverless computing"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Network optimization"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the purpose of Azure Key Vault ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Securely store and manage sensitive information such as secrets and keys"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Monitor and analyze performance metrics of Azure resources"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Host web applications and APIs in a scalable and reliable manner"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Provide identity and access management for Azure AD"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"A",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following is Not a type of storage offered by Azure Storage Accounts ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Blob Storage"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Queue Storage"
                },
                {
                    "C":"File Storage"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Document Storage"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is a limitation of the Azure Functions Consumption Plan ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"It cannot run Docker containers"
                },
                {
                    "B":"It only supports C# and JavaScript"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Since it is a function app hosted in consumption plan , it cannot be subscribed by event consumers"
                },
                {
                    "D":"It does not support VNET integration"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"How does Azure Functions pricing model primarily work ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Based on the number of VMs used"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Based on the amount of storage used"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Based on the number of executions and execution time"
                },
                {
                    "D":"A flat monthly fee"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the hightest scope at which you can assign an RBAC role in Azure ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Subscription"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Resource Group"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Individual Resource"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Management Group"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the primary function of Role-Based Access Control in Azure ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Billing management"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Providing VPN access"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Managing user access to resources"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Data encryption"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which Azure Storage redundancy option provides the highest level of data durability across multiple regions ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Locally-redundant storage (LRS)"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Zone-redundant storage (ZRS)"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Geo-redundant storage (GRS)"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Read-access geo-redundant storage (RA-GRS)"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"In Azure Functions, what triggers a function to run ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"A specific time interval"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Manual invocation"
                },
                {
                    "C":"An event in another service"
                },
                {
                    "D":"All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which protocol is NOT supported by Azure AD B2C for authentication ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"OAuth 2.0"
                },
                {
                    "B":"SAML"
                },
                {
                    "C":"OpenID Connect"
                },
                {
                    "D":"FTP"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following are the networking strategies to connect to the Azure Storage Account ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Public endpoint"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Service endpoint on vnet and firewall on vnets"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Private Endpoints"
                },
                {
                    "D":"All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"D",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following are the most recommended secured networking strategies to connect to the Azure Storage Account ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Service endpoint on vnet and firewall on vnets"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Private endpoint"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Both A & B"
                },
                {
                    "D":"None of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"B",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which feature in Azure Blob Storage provides encryption at rest ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Storage Service Encryption (SSE)"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Advanced Threat Protection (ATP)"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Azure Information Protection (AIP)"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"A",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"In Azure AD B2C custom policies, which policy key is used to integrate with external identity providers ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"ClaimsExchange"
                },
                {
                    "B":"UserJourneyBehaviors"
                },
                {
                    "C":"RelyingParty"
                },
                {
                    "D":"ClaimsSchema"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"A",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"How does Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 enhance Azure Blob Storage ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"By providing blockchain storage solutions"
                },
                {
                    "B":"By offering a hierarchical namespace for big data analytics"
                },
                {
                    "C":"By enabling GPU-accelerated computing"
                },
                {
                    "D":"By supporting exclusive virtual network deployments"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"B",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What is a unique feature of Azure Durable Functions compared to standard Azure Functions ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Stateful orchestration of function executions"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Higher memory capacity"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Automatic scaling based on CPU usage"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Integrated Visual Studio support"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"A",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following statements about AAD B2C are true ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Guest users can only sign in to single tenant B2C"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Consumers can sign in from common endpoint in multi-tenant Azure AD "
                },
                {
                    "C":"Both A and B"
                },
                {
                    "D":"None of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following things we can accomplish with Microsoft Graph ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"User Migration"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Calculate the intersection points in user's addresses"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Both A and B"
                },
                {
                    "D":"None of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"A",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"What Azure Devops doesn't primarily offer ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"A set of tools for building and deploying applications"
                },
                {
                    "B":"A set of tools for testing applications"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Virtual Machines administration for self hosted agents"
                },
                {
                    "D":"None of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which Azure service is used for real-time analytics on streaming data and can process millions of events per second ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Azure Machine learning"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Azure Event Hubs"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Azure Databricks"
                },
                {
                    "D":"Azure Data Lake Analytics"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"B",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following azure service uses the TCP connection to connect to the client ?",
            "options":[
                {
                    "A":"Table storage"
                },
                {
                    "B":"Blob storage"
                },
                {
                    "C":"Redis cache"
                },
                {
                    "D":"All of the above"
                }
            ],
            "answer":"C",
            "isTieBreaker":false
        }
    ]
}